GABRIEL BUENO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

gabibueno00@gmail.com +54 9 3513893463 LinkedIn: <u>/gabrielbueno92</u> Github: <u>/gabrielbueno92</u>

PROFILE SUMMARY

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering with 2+ years of experience working as a Backend Developer (Java, Spring, Maven, MySQL, API Rest). Knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and React. Passion for technology and acquiring new insights every day.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Dart, Javascript, HTML5, CSS.
- Frameworks: Spring, Maven, Hibernate, Flutter, React, Bootstrap
- RESTful API, API Rest, Microservices
- Database: Oracle, SQL, MySQL
- Source and Version Control: Git, Github
- Software testing: JUnit
- Agile Methodology: Scrum
- Project management: Jira, Kanban
- Design patterns

- Analytical and problem-solving
- Team player.
- Collaboration
- Attention to detail.
- Communication.
- · Self motivated.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER MERCADO LIBRE, CORDOBA, ARGENTINA

December, 2018 - August, 2021

- Developed an API about new cancellations metric for sellers, using Java/Spring, MySQL, API Rest, improving the experience of 44M buyers and impacting 12M sellers.
- Redesigned and converted 2 applications developed in Groovy/Grails and hosted in old servers to Java/Spring migrated in the cloud (AWS), freeing up the phisical servers and saving money for the company.
- Debbugged and identified code errors, fixed bugs, reducing the incoming claims from end customers by 85% (Java/Spring, Groovy/Grails, Node.Js, JUnit)
- Collaborated in every sprint planning sessions with product team, UX/UI designers, writing and assigning tasks to work on in the following week (Jira, Kanban, Agile methodology).

INCIDENT MANAGEMENT ANALYST MERCADO LIBRE, CORDOBA, ARGENTINA

December, 2017 - December, 2018

- Analyzed and resolved tickets of possible technical incidents reported of the application related to accounts and users' personal data, writing the cases in which the bug is reproduced and the test cases performed, facilitating problem solving (Postman, Jira, Tableau).
- Documented application functionalities and user manual for a better understanding of it, considerably reducing the number of tickets received by the customer service team (Jira).

SERVICE MANAGEMENT ANALYST NARANJA X, CORDOBA, ARGENTINA

December, 2016 - December, 2017

- Participated in the opening of more than 12 new customer service branches, coordinating, installing and configuring the technological equipment.
- Coordinated and managed the resolution of hardware and business system problems.

PROCESSING AND MONITORING ANALYST NARANJA X, CORDOBA, ARGENTINA

December, 2013 - December, 2016

- Created scripts for updating information between servers (batch, online, testing), and file backup. Automated the execution of processes through a schematization tool (Linux, Ctrl-M, SFTP Protocol).
- Searched and placed tapes in data center and retrieved old files for use by the lawyers' team or for simulations (EMC Networker).
- Monitored the performance of the company's servers and databases, resolving possible service downtimes.

EDUCATION March, 2021

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Universidad Siglo 21, Cordoba, Argentina Status: Completed.

June, 2020

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE IN SOFTWARE ANALYSIS

Universidad Siglo 21, Cordoba, Argentina Status: Completed.

LANGUAGES

Spanish English